Wahab Tlais

Web Developer

Address Baalbeck, 8356 Lebanon

Phone +96170428794

E-mail wahabtlais@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/wahab-

tlais-25bba2249

WWW https://wahabtlais.netlify.app/

Motivated and skilled Junior Web Developer with 2 years of experience in creating Full-Stack websites, e-commerce platforms, and a strong portfolio using a variety of web technologies. Seeking to contribute my technical expertise to a dynamic team while continually enhancing my skills.

Technical Profile

- Microsoft Office
- SQL
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP
- Git
- React

Competencies

Web development projects

Website optimization

Programming Languages

Project Management

Technical Support

Site template development

Web Security

Work History

2021-09 - Current

Web Developer

Freelance/Self-Employed, Baalbek

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ¡Query languages.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL to create dynamic and responsive web applications.

- Collaborated with the team to improve website functionality and optimize the user experience.
- Implemented effective data storage solutions using MySQL databases.
- Used Javascript, SQL and HTML to develop app-solutions.
- Developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of clients.

2023-09 - 2023-10

Web Development Intern

CodSoft, Remotely

- Used content creation tools and digital media to design web sites.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Documented project changes in team manuals for future reference and use.
- Pitched feature improvements to developer team for use in applications.
- Followed best practices for software development and web security.

Education

2022-10 - Current

BBA: Management Information Systems

Islamic University of Lebanon - Baalbek, Lebanon

Languages

Arabic

English

Certifications

Certified Web Developer, CodSoft - 2023

Computer Languages, CIS College, 2022

Web Development & Mobile Application, CIS College, 2022